if you're watching this video from your phone your ipad or any electronic device then i urge
you to keep watching and this is because while our phones and computers and other electronic
devices are truly remarkable if you look inside of them you will find blood there's blood inside
most of these devices because most of our phones contain a mineral called calton at the heart of
every mobile you must go to the congo 1400 kilometers from the capital kinshasa near the
rwandan border in south kivu this region is a geological miracle stuffed full of minerals
and it's ravaged by war four million people have died in the past 13 years the violence feeds off
the abundance of natural resources congo is currently experiencing what many describe as
the silent holocaust and millions of people have been unalived including women and children just
so that the western world can profit off of its natural resources approximately 80 percent of the
world's supply of calton comes from congo because of this multinational companies aren't saving people in
congo the places where this ore is found are often occupied by foreigners and the mineral is a form of
currency there are two aspects to the problem the political side and the economic side the political
side is the fact that there are always foreigners on congolese soil they should leave this land and
return home but in the meantime they're stealing from the congolese the foreigners are getting rich
rich but not the ordinary congolese western countries such as the us uk and france have been providing
financial military aid to uganda and rwanda to invade regions filled with cults and reserves and as they
invade millions of people are unalived aside from the millions of people who have lost their lives half of
which are children 48 women are essayed every single hour the workers are adolescents who slave
like convicts do you know what coltan is used for no we don't really know we know it's a mineral
every able-bodied young person in the village must dig the mountain they have no choice the mine is the
only way to earn a living how old are you 15 some are just young children as in a gold mine the earth
is washed several times the impurities are washed away leaving gray sand dotted with little black pebbles
this is the coltan that the armed groups want so much not long ago they came to get it with weapons
as anatole the village head map remembers for those of you who've watched this far thank you so much for
watching make sure you comment like and share this video so that other people can also learn about
what's happening in congo what is happening in congo is super tragic and millions of people have
already lost their lives as a result neo-colonialism and imperialism are at the heart of what is happening
in congo the first thing that we need to do is we need to make sure that the companies we buy our
devices from use ethically sourced coltan and if these companies don't then we need to pressure them
into doing so by making it known that we will no longer buy devices that contain the blood of our
congo bees brothers and sisters i'm going to try to find a list of companies that use unethically
sourced coltan in the next few days and i'll make a video about it soon i also recommend this book
called the divide by jason hickle i rave about this book all the time although this book doesn't
specifically talk about what's happening in congo it explains neo-colonialism and global inequalities
in a way that i've never seen being explained before so i highly recommend everyone reads this book
i also recommend everyone watches this movie called blood diamond i actually just watched a
documentary called blood coltan to educate myself about what's going on in congo but it doesn't
describe all the moving parts as well as this movie does this movie is set in sierra leone and it is
about the diamond industry instead of the coltan industry however there are so many parallels and
similarities that i think watching this movie would be very insightful let me know if i missed anything and
please stay tuned for the next video